瓦雷利亚末日
伊耿一世（AC1-37 在位）
“征服者”
坦格利安家族征服维斯特洛
雷妮丝
伊耿一世的妹妹和妻子
伊尼斯一世（AC37-42 在位）
杰赫里斯一世（AC48-103 在位）
“和解者”“人瑞王”
亚莉珊（AC36-100）
“善良王后”
杰赫里斯一世的妹妹和妻子
贝尔隆（AC57-101）
“勇敢的”“春晓王子”
杰赫里斯一世的儿子和国王之手
阿莱莎（AC60-84）
贝尔隆的妹妹和妻子
戴蒙
“浪荡王子”
贝尔隆的儿子 韦赛里斯一世的弟弟
科利斯·瓦列利安
“海蛇”“潮汛之主”
雷妮丝
“无冕女王”
韦赛里斯一世的堂姐
韦赛里斯一世
“安宁王”
奥托·海塔尔
伊耿二世的国王之手
阿莉森·海塔尔
奥托的女儿 韦赛里斯一世的第二任妻子
伊耿二世
“大伊耿”
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的长子
海伦娜·坦格利安
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的女儿
大伊耿的妻子
伊蒙德·坦格利安
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的次子
戴伦·坦格利安
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的三子
阿莉森·海塔尔
奥托的女儿 韦赛里斯一世的第二任妻子
伊耿二世
“大伊耿”
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的长子
伊蒙德·坦格利安
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的次子
海伦娜·坦格利安
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的长女
大伊耿的妻子
伊耿·坦格利安
“小伊耿”
戴蒙和雷妮拉的长子
韦赛里斯·坦格利安
戴蒙和雷妮拉的次子
改编自 《血与火：坦格利安王朝史》
[美] 乔治·马丁 著
原著简体中文译者  屈畅  赵琳
龙 王 家 族
第一季 第十集
黑女王 The Black Queen
临 冬 城
颈泽
卡林湾
艾林谷
路斯里斯·瓦列利安
雷妮拉与兰尼诺的次子
女泉镇
鸦栖堡
潮头岛
你在这儿
There you are.
雷妮拉·坦格利安
“王国之光” 韦赛里斯一世的继承人
海蛇快要死了 对不对？
The Sea Snake is going to die, isn't he?
- 小路 - 我当不了潮汛之主
-Luke-- -I can't be Lord of the Tides.
祖父是有史以来最伟大的航海家
Grandsire was the greatest sailor who ever lived.
可我呢 船还没离港就会晕船
I get greensick before the ship even leaves the harbor.
我会搞砸所有事
I'll just ruin everything.
我也不想要潮头岛
I don't want Driftmark.
本该由魏蒙德爵士继承
It should've passed on to Ser Vaemond.
小路 我们无法选择自己的命运 是命运选择了我们
We don't choose our destiny, Luke. It chooses us.
但外公曾让您选择是否要继承王位
Grandsire let you choose whether you'd be his heir.
您是这样告诉我们的
You told us so.
那你想知道真实的情况吗？
And do you want to know the truth of it?
我当时吓坏了
I was frightened.
当年我才十四岁
I was four-and-ten.
和你现在一样大
Same as you are now.
我并未做好准备 成为七大王国的女王
I wasn't ready to be Queen of the Seven Kingdoms.
但这是我的职责所在
But it was my duty.
很快地 我就明白了
And, in time, I came to understand
我得靠自己赢得继承权
I had to earn my inheritance.
我和您不一样
I'm not like you.
哪些方面 好孩子？
In what way, sweet boy?
我不像您那么...
I'm not so...
完美
perfect.
我绝不完美
I am anything but.
我父亲照顾我 帮助我做好继承的准备
My father looked after me and helped to prepare me for my duties.
你的母亲也会为你做同样的事情
Your mother will do the same for you.
早上好 公主殿下
Good morrow, Princess.
早上好 洛伦特爵士
Good morrow, Ser Lorent.
洛伦特·马尔布兰
御林铁卫
雷妮丝公主刚刚骑龙抵达
Princess Rhaenys has just arrived on dragonback.
她请求立即与您和戴蒙王子见面
She urgently requests an audience with you and Prince Daemon.
雷妮丝·坦格利安公主到
The Princess Rhaenys Targaryen.
谢谢你 洛伦特爵士
Thank you, Ser Lorent.
雷妮丝·坦格利安
“无冕女王” 雷妮拉的堂姑 科利斯的妻子
雷妮丝公主
Princess Rhaenys,
或许您带来了科利斯伯爵康复的消息？
might we hope for news of Lord Corlys's recovery?
韦赛里斯死了
Viserys is dead.
戴蒙·坦格利安
“浪荡王子” 雷妮拉的叔叔和丈夫
我与你同感悲痛 雷妮拉
I grieve this loss with you, Rhaenyra.
我的堂弟 你的父亲
My cousin, your father...
他有颗善良的心
possessed a kind heart.
还有别的坏消息
There is more.
伊耿已继位 加冕为王
Aegon has been crowned as his successor.
他们给伊耿加冕了？
They crowned him?
韦赛里斯怎么死的？
How did Viserys die?
这个我不知道
I could not say.
多久前的事？
How long ago?
一天前 顶多两天
A day past, perhaps two.
当王后密谋一切时 我被软禁在房间里
I was made a prisoner in my quarters while the Queen made her preparations.
韦赛里斯是被他们害死的
Viserys has been slain.
阿莉森要求你支持伊耿
Alicent demanded you declare for Aegon.
没错
She did.
我拒绝了她
I refused her.
然而你还活着
And yet you are alive.
总主教在龙穴为伊耿加冕
The High Septon crowned Aegon in the Dragonpit.
我亲眼目睹了仪式 之后骑上梅丽亚斯离开了
I witnessed it myself just before I fled on Meleys.
他们当着民众的面拥他为王
They crowned him before the masses.
因此民众把他视作合法的国王
So that the masses would see him as their rightful king.
王后那贱人谋害了我哥哥 还篡夺了王位
That whore of a Queen murdered my brother and stole his throne.
你本可以把他们全烧死
And you could have burned them all for it.
当然 他们的叛国行径很可能引发战争
A war is like to be fought over this treachery, to be sure.
但这场战争不会由我挑起
But that war is not mine to begin.
我只是赶来警告你们
I only rushed this warning to you
因为我忠于我的丈夫和我的家族
out of loyalty to my husband and to my house.
绿党冲着你来了 雷妮拉
The Greens are coming for you, Rhaenyra.
还有你的孩子们
And for your children.
你们应该马上离开龙石岛
You should leave Dragonstone at once.
孩子要出生了
The babe is coming.
格拉底斯
龙石岛的学士
伊莲达·马赛
雷妮拉的侍女
还没足月 预产期还远
Her term is far from complete.
不该现在生的
This should not be happening.
操 已经在生了
It is fucking happening.
请冷静 公主殿下 来吧
Keep your head about you, Princess. Come.
我们生过五次了
We've done this five times before.
请您打起精神来 这次也会一样的
Keep your spirit, and the sixth will be no different.
走开 走开 走开 都走开
Get off, get off, get off, get off!
啊 啊 啊
Ow, ow, ow.
派人沿着龙石岛周边巡逻
I want patrols along the island's perimeter,
留意任何意图靠岸的小船
looking for any small ships that might set ashore.
如果绿党现在发动进攻 必然是一场偷袭……
If the Greens attack now, it will be by stealth...
绝非大张旗鼓
not directly.
现在我们人手不足 无法覆盖全岛
We don't have enough men to surround the island,
但至少可以造大声势
but we can make ourselves appear stronger than they are.
征召龙卫 他们是强有力的战士
Conscript the Dragonkeepers. They're capable fighters.
别浪费时间
Waste no time.
马上去办 王子殿下
It will be done, my Prince.
这 算 什么？
What was that?
对不起
I'm sorry.
史蒂芬·达克林
御林铁卫
杰卡里斯·瓦列利安
雷妮拉与兰尼诺的长子
不必对他太严格 王子殿下
You might go easier on him, my Prince,
那样他才能学会您想教的
so he can learn what you're trying to teach.
你们的母亲想要见你们
Your lady mother needs to see you!
两位都去
Both of you.
母亲？
Mother?
操
Fuck.
公主殿下
Princess.
你们的外公 韦赛里斯国王 已经去世了
Your grandsire, King Viserys, has passed.
韦赛里斯？
Viserys?
绿党不承认继承顺位
The Greens have repudiated the succession
占据了铁王座
and claimed the Iron Throne.
伊耿已经称王了
Aegon has been crowned king.
我们要做什么？
What is to be done about it?
现在还不用
Nothing yet.
戴蒙在哪儿？
And where is Daemon?
我不知道
I don't know.
他气得发狂
Gone to madness.
在谋划战争
Gone to plot his war.
我去找戴蒙
Leave Daemon with me.
小杰
Jace.
杰卡里斯
Jacaerys.
不管我还拥有什么 你都是我的继承人了
Whatever claim remains to me, you are now its heir.
没有我的命令 不要轻举妄动
Naught is to be done but by my command.
今早有渡鸦来报
A raven flew in this morning.
海蛇已经退烧 并离开了暮临厅
The Sea Snake's fever has broken, and he has left Evenfall.
他驶去哪了？
Where is he sailing?
那就不清楚了 殿下
That much is unclear, my Prince.
我们要向最近的盟友送出渡鸦：
We'll send ravens to our nearest allies:
达克林大人 马赛大人……
Lords Darklyn, Massey...
还有巴尔艾蒙
and Bar Emmon.
戴蒙！
Daemon!
巴提摩斯·赛提加
蟹岛伯爵
你要跟学士谈一下吗 王子？
Do you want to speak to the maester, my Prince?
我会亲自飞去河间地 确保徒利大人的支持
I'll fly to the Riverlands myself and affirm Lord Tully's support.
你不能这么做
You will do no such thing.
我母亲下令 在其卧床期间 不许采取行动
My mother has decreed no action be taken while she's abed.
你来的正好 小王子
It's good you're here, young Prince.
需要你骑上沃马克斯 巡逻空域
You're needed to patrol the skies on Vermax.
没听到我说的话？
Did you hear what I said?
渡鸦 巴提摩斯大人
The ravens, Lord Bartimos.
马上督办
I shall see it done.
传唤史蒂芬爵士
Summon Ser Steffon.
御林铁卫跟我去一趟龙山
Our Kingsguard are needed on the Dragonmont.
跟我来 我给你看看忠诚真正的意义
Come with me. I'll show you the true meaning of loyalty.
你们作为御林铁卫曾宣过誓
You swore an oath as knights of the Kingsguard.
所有白骑士都是如此 王子
As do all who wear the white cloak, my Prince.
对谁？
To whom?
我先是对杰赫里斯国王宣誓 王子
I swore first to King Jaehaerys, my Prince.
然后是对继位的韦赛里斯国王陛下
And then to His Grace, King Viserys, when he succeeded him.
你们认可真正的继承顺位吗
Do you acknowledge the true line of succession?
-认可 -认可 殿下
-Yes. -Yes, my Prince.
那你们还记得
Do you recall
韦赛里斯国王驾崩前指定谁为他的继承人吗？
who King Viserys named as his heir before his death?
雷妮拉公主
Princess Rhaenyra.
我感谢你们对朝廷多年的效力
I'm grateful for your long service to the crown.
所以我赐予你们一个选择
So I'm presenting you with a choice.
科拉克休
戴蒙的龙
重新宣誓效忠 对雷妮拉女王
Swear anew your oath to Rhaenyra as your queen...
及铁王座继承人杰卡里斯王子
to Prince Jacaerys as the heir to the Iron Throne
或者……
Or...
如果你们支持篡位者 那现在就明说……
if you support the usurper, speak it now...
不但能死得痛快 还能不失荣誉
and you will have a clean and honorable death.
但如果你们若选择背信弃义
But if you choose treachery,
现在假意宣誓 以后再行叛变
if you swear fealty now only to later turn your cloaks...
必将惨叫而死
know that you will die...screaming.
公主 让我们帮帮你吧
Princess, let us help you.
不
No.
- 出去！ - 公主 求您了
- Get out! - Princess, please.
- 出去 - 您没必要自己受罪 公主
- Get out. - You should not do this alone, Princess.
让我们帮忙吧
Let us help you.
乔佛里·瓦列利安
雷妮拉与兰尼诺的三子
我没有敌意 兄弟们
I mean no harm, brothers.
伊利克·卡盖尔
亚历克的孪生兄弟 御林铁卫
此为韦赛里斯一世的黄金王冠，有别于伊耿二世所戴的“征服者”伊耿一世的瓦雷利亚钢王冠。
我对女王庄严起誓
I swear to ward the Queen...
我将尽心竭力守护她
with all my strength...
付出生命在所不惜
and give my blood for hers.
我将不娶妻……
I shall take no wife...
不封地……
hold no lands...
不生子
father no children.
我将守护她的秘密
I shall guard her secrets...
服从她的命令……
obey her commands...
追随她鞍前马后 维护她的名声和荣誉
ride at her side, and defend her name and honor.
女王陛下
My Queen.
后排右一教士胸前的高等瓦雷利亚文字意为“教士”。
贝妮拉·坦格利安
戴蒙与兰娜尔的长女
雷妮亚·坦格利安
戴蒙与兰娜尔的次女
白港
托伦方城
卡林湾
先民荒冢
艾林谷
颈泽
临冬城
荒石城
海疆城
奔流城
赫伦堡
荒冢屯
高尚之心
美人集
灰水望
孪河城
咬人湾
橡果厅
石堂镇
铁民湾
十塔城
鹰巢城
峭岩城
黑水河
深穴城
深林堡
菲林特之指
暮谷镇
金牙城
萨斯菲尔德城
银厅
恐怖堡
影子塔
罗斯比城
君临
凯岩城
烙印城
苦桥
鸦栖堡
女泉镇
岑树滩
兰
尼
斯
港
果酒厅
红垒
东海望
最后壁炉城
黑城堡
老锚地
金树城
雷妮拉·坦格利安一世
Queen Rhaenyra Targaryen, First of Her Name,
安达尔人 洛伊拿人和先民的女王
Queen of the Andals and the Rhoynar and the First Men.
七国统治者暨全境守护者 驾到
Lady of the Seven Kingdoms and Protector of the Realm.
陛下
Your Grace.
酒 陛下
Wine, my Queen.
谢谢你 雷妮亚
Thank you, Rhaena.
来
Come.
- 我们情况如何？- 我们有三十名骑士
-What is our standing? -We have 30 knights,
一百名十字弓手 三百名士兵
a hundred crossbowmen, and 300 men-at-arms.
防守龙石岛是足够了 但要凭此征讨四方
Dragonstone is relatively easy to defend, but as an instrument of conquest,
我们还需要更多军队
our army leaves a lot to be desired.
我已经传话给都城守备队中忠于我的人
We have sent word to my loyal men in the City Watch.
我会得到一些支持 但不确定有多少
I'll have some support there, but I cannot speak to the numbers.
公开宣誓我们的家族有赛提加 斯汤顿
We already have declarations from Celtigar and Staunton,
马赛 达克林和巴尔艾蒙
Massey, Darklyn, Bar Emmon.
我母后出自艾林家
My lady mother was an Arryn.
谷地不会反叛血亲
The Vale will not turn cloak against their own kin.
奔流城公爵向来是您父亲的密友 陛下
Riverrun was always a close friend to your father, Your Grace.
经戴蒙王子准许
With Prince Daemon's acquiescence,
我已经派渡鸦给葛拉佛大人送信
I've already sent ravens to Lord Grover.
葛拉佛大人反复无常 容易动摇
Lord Grover is fickle and easily swayed.
我们需要用实力说服他
He will need to be convinced of the strength of our position
并确保一旦开战 我们会支援他
and that we will support him should it come to war.
我会亲自与他交涉
I'm going to treat with him myself.
那风息堡和临冬城呢？
What of Storm's End and Winterfell?
史塔克家的人从不忘记誓言
There has never lived a Stark who forgot an oath.
只要有了史塔克的支持 全北境就会追随
And with House Stark, the North will follow.
需要提醒博洛斯·拜拉席恩大人 他父亲立过誓
Lord Borros Baratheon will need to be reminded of his father's promises.
临 冬 城
罗斯比城
女泉镇
龙石岛
鸦栖堡
潮头岛
暮谷城
潮头岛有什么消息？
What news from Driftmark?
科利斯大人正航向龙石岛
Lord Corlys sails for Dragonstone.
来向他的女王宣誓效忠
To declare for his Queen.
瓦列里安家族舰队在我丈夫轭下
The Velaryon fleet is in my husband's yoke.
他会决定航向
He decides where they sail.
我们会祈祷你和你丈夫的支持
We shall pray for both you and your husband's support.
就像我们每夜祈祷海蛇的康复
Just as we prayed nightly for the Sea Snake's return to good health.
狭海沿岸没有哪个港口
There's no port on the Narrow Sea would dare to make
敢与瓦列利安舰队为敌
an enemy of the Velaryon fleet.
那我们的敌人呢？
And our enemies?
兰尼斯特家族里找不到朋友
We have no friends among the Lannisters.
泰兰效力于国王之手已久 不可能掉转矛头
Tyland has served the Hand too long to turn against him.
奥托·海塔尔也需要兰尼斯特的舰队
And Otto Hightower needs the Lannister fleet.
没有兰尼斯特家族 我们在金牙城以西
Without the Lannisters, we are not like to find
不太可能找到盟友
any allies west of the Golden Tooth.
金牙城
美人集
橡果厅
黑水河
峭岩城
石堂镇
高尚之心
萨斯菲尔德城
奔流城
赫伦堡
没错
No.
河间地是关键 陛下
The Riverlands are essential, Your Grace.
恕我直言 陛下 只数人头是无意义的
Pray forgive my bluntness, Your Grace, but talk of men is moot.
您拥有自古瓦雷利亚毁灭以来
Your cause owns a power that has not been seen in this world
世所罕见的强大力量
since the days of Old Valyria.
龙
Dragons.
绿党也有龙
The Greens have dragons as well.
我数过 他们有三条成年龙
They have three adults, by my count.
而我们有叙拉克斯 科拉克休 和梅丽亚斯
We have Syrax, Caraxes, and Meleys.
你的儿子们有沃马克斯 阿拉克斯和泰雷克休
Your sons have Vermax, Arrax, and Tyraxes.
贝妮拉有月舞
Baela has Moondancer.
戴蒙 我们的龙没上过战场
Daemon, none of our dragons have been to war.
还有无主的龙
There are also unclaimed dragons.
海烟仍然栖息在潮头岛
Seasmoke still resides on Driftmark.
沃米索尔和银翼住在龙山
Vermithor and Silverwing dwell on the Dragonmont,
依然无人驯服
still riderless.
还有三只野龙在这里筑巢
Then there are the three wild dragons, all of whom nest here.
那么谁来做骑手？
And who is to ride them?
龙石岛有十三条龙 他们只有四条
Dragonstone has 13 to their 4.
我还有二十颗龙蛋 正在龙山孵化
I also have a score of eggs incubating in the Dragonmont.
现在……我们需要一个据点
Now... we need a place to gather,
一个足够大的立足点 来集结大军
a toehold large enough to house a sizable host.
白港
艾林谷
鹰巢城
先民荒冢
奔流城
赫伦堡
君临
临冬城
铜门城
风息堡
苦桥
岑树滩
金树城
孪河城
萨斯菲尔德城
石堂镇
高尚之心
橡果厅
黑水河
深穴城
银厅
荒石城
美人集
老锚地
咬人湾
卡林湾
恐怖堡
红垒
潮头岛
龙石岛
罗斯比城
暮谷城
女泉镇
鸦栖堡
海鸥镇
恐穴堡
灰水望
托伦方城
荒冢屯
这里 赫伦堡
Here, at Harrenhal.
我们切断西路 让龙包围君临
We cut off the west, surround King's Landing with the dragons.
便可以在下个月前
And we could have every Green head mounted on spikes
把绿党的脑袋统统插到枪尖上
before the fucking moon turns.
陛下
Your Grace...
我们在岸边发现船只
a ship has been sighted offshore:
一艘独行的帆船 挂着三头绿龙旗
a lone galleon, flying a banner of a three-headed green dragon.
通知瞭望塔 警戒天空
Alert the watchtowers. Sight the skies.
我奉七国的统治者与守护者
I come at the behest of the Dowager Queen Alicent,
奥托·海塔尔
阿莉森太后的父亲 国王之手
国王伊耿二世之母后
mother of King Aegon, Second of His Name,
阿莉森王太后之命前来
Lord and Protector of the Seven Kingdoms.
太后命我仅将此信息传达给雷妮拉公主本人
I've been directed to deliver her message only to Princess Rhaenyra.
公主在哪？
Where is the Princess?
叙拉克斯
雷妮拉的龙
雷妮拉公主
Princess Rhaenyra.
我现在是雷妮拉女王了
I'm Queen Rhaenyra now.
尔等都是王国的叛徒
And you all are traitors to the realm.
伊耿·坦格利安二世国王陛下
King Aegon Targaryen, Second of His Name...
怀着仁慈和对和平的渴望
in his wisdom and desire for peace,
提出和谈条件
is offering terms.
承认伊耿为王
Acknowledge Aegon as king
在铁王座前向国王宣誓效忠
and swear obeisance before the Iron Throne.
作为交换 陛下将承认你对龙石岛的所有权
In exchange, His Grace will confirm your possession of Dragonstone.
在你死后 龙石岛将传予你的嫡子 杰卡里斯
It will pass to your trueborn son, Jacaerys, upon your death.
路斯里斯将被确认为潮头岛和
Lucerys will be confirmed as the legitimate heir to Driftmark
瓦列利安家族领地与财产的合法继承人
and all the lands and holdings of House Velaryon.
你与戴蒙王子所生之子
Your sons by Prince Daemon
也将获得御前职务的殊荣
will also be given places of high honor at court:
小伊耿将成为国王的侍从
Aegon the Younger as the King's squire,
韦赛里斯将成为国王的侍酒
Viserys as his cupbearer.
最后 国王出于仁慈
Finally, the King, in his good grace,
将赦免所有密谋反对他登基的骑士和领主
will pardon any knight or lord who conspired against his ascent.
我宁可把儿子们扔去喂龙
I would rather feed my sons to the dragons
我也不会让他们为你那篡位的酒鬼贱种国王执盾或者斟酒
than have them carry shields and cups for your drunken, usurper cunt of a king.
伊耿·坦格利安坐在铁王座上
Aegon Targaryen sits the Iron Throne.
戴征服者之冠
He wears the Conqueror's crown,
执征服者之剑
wields the Conqueror's sword,
冠征服者之名
has the Conqueror's name.
他在万千民众的见证下由教会修士涂油加冕
He was anointed by a septon of the Faith before the eyes of thousands.
集一切正统于一身
Every symbol of legitimacy belongs to him.
还有史塔克 徒利和拜拉席恩
And then there is Stark, Tully, Baratheon.
陛下对这些家族开出了优厚的条件
Houses that have also received, and are at present,
值得他们好好考虑一番
considering generous terms from their king.
韦赛里斯陛下立我为继承人时
Stark, Tully, and Baratheon all swore to me
史塔克 徒利和拜拉席恩都曾向我宣誓效忠
when King Viserys named me his heir.
过时的誓言不会让你坐上铁王座 公主
Stale oaths will not put you on the Iron Throne, Princess.
你父亲生出儿子的那一天 继承顺位就改变了
The succession changed the day your father sired a son.
亚历克·卡盖尔
伊利克的孪生兄弟 御林铁卫
只有你和他还在自欺欺人 我真是感到遗憾
I only regret that you and he were the last to see the truth of it.
你不再是首相 伊耿也不是国王
You are no more Hand than Aegon is king.
可恶的叛徒
Fucking traitor.
大学士
Grand Maester.
欧维尔
大学士
这是什么？
What the fuck is this?
娜梅莉亚的舰队
虽然用缆索
捆在一起，
但还是在
第一次
风暴来袭时
被冲散到
海上四处：
东方、
西方，
乃至向南
到了
海盗肆虐的
蛇蜥群岛。
阿莉森太后并没有忘记你们曾经对彼此的爱
Queen Alicent has not forgotten the love you once had for each other.
无需流血牺牲 王国的和平将一如过去
No blood need be spilled, so the realm can carry on in peace.
王太后急切地盼望着你的回复
Queen Alicent eagerly awaits your answer.
她现在就可以得到回答 就用她父亲皱巴巴的鸡巴
She can have her answer now, stuffed in her father's mouth
塞在他自己的嘴里作为答复
along with his withered cock.
让我们结束这场闹剧吧
Let's end this mummer's farce.
伊利克爵士 把海塔尔大人押过来 我要亲自动手
Ser Erryk, bring me Lord Hightower so I may take the pleasure myself.
不
No.
明天 君临会收到我的答复
King's Landing will have my answer on the morrow.
人类要当屠龙者难于登天
It's no easy thing for a man to be a dragonslayer.
可龙杀得了龙 而且确实杀过
But dragons can kill dragons. And have.
一个简单的事实 我们比伊耿拥有更多龙
The simple truth is this: we have more dragons than Aegon.
韦赛里斯经常谈起瓦雷利亚的历史
Viserys spoke often of the Valyrian histories.
我再了解不过
I know them well.
当巨龙飞赴战场……
When dragons flew to war...
一切陷入火海
everything burned.
我不想统治一个灰烬与白骨的王国
I do not wish to rule over a kingdom of ash and bone.
你在考虑海塔尔的条件吗 陛下？
Are you considering the Hightowers' terms, Your Grace?
作为女王 我对王国的真正责任是什么 巴提摩斯伯爵？
As Queen, what is my true duty to the realm, Lord Bartimos?
确保和平与团结？
Ensuring peace and unity?
还是不计一切代价坐稳铁王座？
Or that I sit the Iron Throne, no matter the cost?
那是你父亲的说法
That's your father talking.
我父亲死了
My father's dead.
而他选择我作为继承人
And he chose me as his successor...
去守护王国 而不是让它一头冲入战争
to defend the realm, not cast it headlong into war.
但敌人已经宣战
Well, the enemy have declared war.
你要怎么做？
What are you gonna do about it?
所有人退下
Clear the room.
战争的可能性让你兴奋了吗
Does the promise of war excite you?
你不能向海塔尔屈膝
You cannot bend the knee to the Hightowers.
他们窃取了你与生俱来的权利
They stole your birthright.
如果不必把奥托·海塔尔的头插在枪上
If you could take the Iron Throne
就能拿下铁王座 你会这样做吗？
without putting Otto Hightower's head on a spike, would you?
你不愤怒吗？
Are you not angry?
因为愤怒我就要宣战？
I should declare war because I'm angry?
不
No.
因为镇压叛乱是你作为女王的职责
Because it's your duty as Queen to crush rebellion.
你明白我的誓言应凌驾于个人野心之上
You know my oath reaches beyond our personal ambitions.
冰与火之歌
A Song of Ice and Fire.
什么？
What?
将来在北境 与黑暗的决战
The coming war against the darkness in the North,
征服者的梦
The Conqueror's Dream.
这是韦赛里斯指定我为继承人时告诉我的
Viserys shared it with me when he named me heir.
我哥哥……是征兆和预言的奴隶
My brother... was a slave to his omens and portents.
他软弱统治之时 总认为事出有因
Anything to make his feckless reign appear to have purpose.
让我们成王的不是梦
Dreams didn't make us kings.
是龙
Dragons did.
他从没告诉过你……
He never told you...
是不是？
did he?
科利斯·瓦列利安
“海蛇”“潮汛之主” 潮头岛伯爵
要是哪个爷们当职时睡着了 肯定要挨我一顿鞭子
I've had men whipped for falling asleep on their watch.
但你不是爷们
You are no man.
你抛弃了我……
You abandoned me...
在我最需要你的时候
when I most needed you.
我们的两个孩子都被偷走了
Both our children stolen from us.
当时我需要你
I needed you.
贝妮拉和雷妮娅需要你
Baela and Rhaena needed you,
但你却为了出海冒险而抛弃了我们
and you abandoned us for more adventure at sea.
恰如你一贯的风格
As has always been your way.
我无处可去
I had no other place to turn.
我失去了一切
I lost everything.
是我们 科利斯
We lost, Corlys.
我们
We.
据说我们有新国王了
I understand we have a new king.
我们家族被陌客投下了绵长的阴影
The Stranger casts a long shadow over this family.
你弟弟也死了
Your brother is also dead.
因为他迫不及待想埋葬你 抢你的位子
In his haste to bury you and claim your seat,
他在国王陛下面前
he stood before the King
当众宣称兰尼诺的孩子们是私生子
and denounced Laenor's sons as illegitimate.
戴蒙为此砍了他的脑袋
Daemon took his head for it.
肆无忌惮的野心素来是瓦列利安家的弱点
Heedless ambition has always been a Velaryon weakness.
你是对的 雷妮丝
You were right, Rhaenys.
我要的太多了 结果都是徒劳
I reached too far. And for nothing.
我们对铁王座的追求……结束了
Our pursuit of the Iron Throne... is at an end.
我们不会站到任何一边
We shall declare for no one.
我们就退守高潮城
We will retire to High Tide
享受与孙辈的……天伦之乐 还有——
to be content...with our grandchildren and--
小杰 小路和小乔都有权继承王座
Jace, Luke, and Joff are claimants to the throne.
只要伊耿还是国王 男孩子们就有危险
Those boys'll not be safe so long as Aegon is king.
咱儿子的死 雷妮拉难脱干系
Rhaenyra was complicit in our son's death.
那女孩儿将身边的一切摧毁殆尽
That girl destroys everything she touches.
那"女孩儿"……
That "girl"...
如今正将王国上下团结在一起
is holding the realm together at present.
围着地图桌的所有男人
Every man standing 'round the Painted Table
都在催促她把王国推入战争泥潭
urges her to plunge the realm into war.
雷妮拉是唯一表现出克制的人
Rhaenyra's the only one who's demonstrated restraint.
战争的目的就是填满墓穴 亲爱的斯汤顿伯爵
The purpose of war is to fill graveyards, my dear Lord Staunton.
窍门在于怎么让敌方入土的人比我方多
The trick is to put more of their men in the ground than your own.
你说得轻巧 只因你身为领主
Easy words for a lord who commands
可以安坐在城堡里发令
from the safety of his castle.
这不会让这话反映的真相削减半分……
Doesn't make it any less true.
潮汛之主驾到！
The Lord of the Tides!
科利斯·瓦列利安伯爵……
Lord Corlys Velaryon...
及夫人 雷妮丝·坦格利安公主
and his wife, the Princess Rhaenys Targaryen.
诸位大人
My lords.
科利斯伯爵
Lord Corlys.
看到您恢复健康 我们深感宽慰
It brings much relief to see you hale and healthy again.
我为您的父亲致哀 公主
I'm very sorry about your father, Princess.
他是个好人
He was a good man.
戴蒙在哪儿
Where is Daemon?
王子还有其他事务要处理
There were other concerns which demanded the Prince's attention.
这些是已经公开效忠您的盟友？
Your declared allies?
- 是的 - 要赢得铁王座 这远远不够
- Yes. -Too few to win a war for the throne.
呃 我们还希望能够获得来自
Well, we would also hope to have the support
- 艾林 拜拉席恩和史塔克家族的支持 - 希望
- of Houses Arryn, Baratheon, and Stark. - Hope...
是傻瓜的盟友
is the fool's ally.
艾林和拜拉席恩家族与我们血脉相连
Both Arryn and Baratheon share blood with my house.
而且他们都曾对我宣誓效忠
But all of them swore oaths to me.
如果我没记错的话
As did House Hightower...
海塔尔家族也曾向你宣誓……
if I remember.
您也一样 科利斯伯爵
As did you, Lord Corlys.
您父亲的王国……
Your father's realm...
是正义和荣誉之国
was one of justice and honor.
我们两家因共同的血脉和事业联合在一起
Our houses are bound by common blood and common cause.
海塔尔的叛国行径必将招致倾覆
This Hightower treason cannot stand.
我的家族和舰队都将全力支持您
You have the full support of our fleet and house.
女王陛下
Your Grace.
不胜光荣 科利斯伯爵
You honor me, Lord Corlys.
雷妮丝公主
Princess Rhaenys.
但是 正如我对封臣们所说
But, as I said to my bannermen
我曾向父亲许诺 要维护王国的强大与团结
I made a promise to my father to hold the realm strong and united.
就算战争无可避免 第一剑也不会由我挥出
If war's first stroke is to fall, it will not be by my hand.
您不准备采取行动？
You do not mean to act?
谨慎而为不代表站着不动
Taking caution does not mean standing fast.
开战之前 我得先分清真正的盟友
I wish to know who my allies are before I send them to war.
我在石阶列岛……拼死征战……
The consequence of my...near-demise in the Stepstones...
终于将其收入囊中
is that we now control them.
这次我特意安排了重兵把守
I took care to fully garrison the territory this time.
用不了几天 我的舰队便可完全封锁航道
A total blockade of the shipping lanes will be in place in days, if not already.
三城同盟会业已溃败
The Triarchy have been routed.
狭海是我们的了
The Narrow Sea is ours.
如果我们进一步封锁喉道
If we further seal the Gullet,
就能切断所有海上航行和贸易
we can cut off all seaborne travel and trade
孤立君临
to King's Landing.
我会骑着梅丽亚斯亲自巡逻喉道
I shall take Meleys and patrol the Gullet myself.
等我们围死狭海
When we drain the Narrow Sea,
就能包围君临
we can surround King's Landing,
围攻红堡
lay siege to the Red Keep,
逼绿党投降
and force the Greens' surrender.
要确保有足够人马包围君临
If we are to have enough swords to surround King's Landing,
我们就必须先得到临冬城 鹰巢城和风息堡的支持
we must first secure the support of Winterfell, the Eyrie, and Storm's End.
我来准备渡鸦传书 陛下
I'll prepare the ravens, Your Grace.
让我们去送信吧
We should bear those messages.
龙飞得比渡鸦快
Dragons can fly faster than ravens
龙也更有说服力
and they're more convincing.
派我们去吧
Send us.
王子说得对 陛下
The Prince is right, Your Grace.
很好
Very well.
杰卡里斯王子向北
Prince Jacaerys will fly north.
先去鹰巢城见我母亲的堂亲 简妮·艾林夫人
First to the Eyrie to see my mother's cousin, the Lady Jeyne Arryn,
然后去临冬城 与克雷根·史塔克大人交涉
and then to Winterfell to treat with Lord Cregan Stark
争取北境的支持
for the support of the North.
路斯里斯王子南下风息堡
Prince Lucerys will fly south to Storm's End
与博洛斯·拜拉席恩大人交涉
and treat with Lord Borros Baratheon.
我们必须提醒这几位大人他们曾立下的誓言
We must remind these lords of the oaths they swore.
以及……背誓的代价
And... the cost of breaking them.
都说坦格利安家族比凡人更接近神
It's been said that as Targaryens, we are closer to gods than to men.
或许铁王座也有一分功劳
And the Iron Throne puts us a touch closer, perhaps.
但如果我们要侍奉七大王国
But, if we are to serve the Seven Kingdoms...
就必须接受他们的神明
we must answer to their gods.
你们要去 只能作为信使 而不是战士
If you take this errand, you go as messengers... not as warriors.
切勿参与任何争斗
You must take no part in any fighting.
现在 就七神的见证下向我发誓吧
Swear it to me now under the eyes of the Seven.
我发誓
I swear it.
谢谢
Thank you.
与我相比 克雷根·史塔克与你更加年龄相仿
Cregan Stark is close to your age than is mine.
希望你们同为男人 能找到一些共同话题
I would hope, that as men, you can find some common interest.
是 陛下
Yes, Your Grace.
风息堡离这不远
Storm's End is a short flight from here.
从你的祖母雷妮丝身上 你传承了拜拉席恩的血脉
You have Baratheon blood from your grandmother, Rhaenys.
此外……
And...
博洛斯大人素来骄傲
Lord Borros is an eternally proud man.
他会感到荣幸 能招待王国的王子
He will be honored to host a prince of the realm...
和他的龙
and his dragon.
我相信你会受到热情款待
I expect you will receive a very warm welcome.
好的 母亲 陛——陛下
Yes, Mother. Y-Your Grace.
去吧
Go to it then.
阿拉克斯
路斯里斯的龙
吞吐火焰 驾驭双翼
Drakari pykiros, Tīkummo jemiros.
双头并立 向三而歌
Yn lantyz bartossa, Saelot vāedis.
由我之声 烈火言语
Hen ñuhā elēnī: Perzyssy vestretis,
血之魔法 牺牲已偿
Se gēlȳn irūdaks, Ānogrose.
火之言辞 辅以明眸
Perzyro udrȳssi, Ezīmptos laehossi.
三者合一 吾向汝歌
Hārossa letagon, Aōt vāedan.
龙之三头 齐聚合一
Hae mērot gierūli: Se hāros bartossi,
命定翱翔 自由美丽
Prūmȳsa sōvīli, Gevī dāerī.
我是路斯里斯·瓦列利安王子
I am Prince Lucerys Velaryon.
我给博洛斯大人带来了女王的信
I bring a message to Lord Borros from the Queen.
路斯里斯·瓦列利安王子到
Prince Lucerys Velaryon.
此乃雷妮拉·坦格利安公主之子
Son of Princess Rhaenyra Targaryen.
伊蒙德·坦格利安
伊耿二世的二弟
博洛斯大人
Lord Borros...
我为您带来了我母亲……
I brought you a message from my mother...
女王陛下的信
the Queen.
可我今天才迎接过国王的使节
Yet earlier this day, I received an envoy from the King.
到底哪位是真的？
Which is it?
国王还是女王？
King or Queen?
龙王家族好像弄不清楚谁来掌权啊 哈哈哈
The House of the Dragon does not seem to know who rules it.
你母亲的信呢？
What's your mother's message?
混蛋学士哪去了？
Where's the bloody maester?
“提醒”我家父的誓言
"Remind" me of my father's oath.
伊耿国王至少还开出了条件
King Aegon at least came with an offer:
用联姻来换取我麾下的骑士和封臣
my swords and banners for a marriage pact.
如果我照你母亲吩咐的做
If I do as your mother bids...
你会娶我哪个女儿？
which one of my daughters will you wed...
小子？
boy?
大人……我无法联姻
My lord... I am not free to marry.
我已有婚约
I'm already betrothed.
所以你空手就来了是吧
So you come with empty hands.
回家吧 小崽子
Go home, pup.
告诉你母亲 风息堡公爵不是她养的狗
And tell your mother that the Lord of Storm's End
用得着时吹吹哨子就能为她撕咬敌人
is not some dog that she can whistle up at need to set against her foes.
我会把您的答复转告给女王的 大人
I shall take your answer to the Queen, my lord.
等等……
Wait...
斯壮大人
my Lord Strong.
你不会真的以为你在王国里随便飞一飞
Did you really think that you could just fly about the realm
不费吹灰之力就能偷走我哥哥的王位吧？
trying to steal my brother's throne at no cost?
我不会和你打架
I will not fight you.
我是以信使的身份而来 不是战士
I came as a messenger, not a warrior.
打架有什么意思
A fight would be little challenge.
不
No.
我要你挖出一只眼睛
I want you to put out your eye.
算是向我赔罪
As payment for mine.
一只就好
One will serve.
我不会让你全瞎的
I would not blind you.
嗯 我好送给母亲当作礼物
Mm, plan to make a gift of it to my mother.
不
No.
你不仅是个懦夫 还是个叛徒
Then you are craven as well as a traitor.
出去吵
Not here.
把你的眼珠子给我
Give me your eye
不然我就亲自动手了 野种！
or I will take it, bastard!
别在我的大厅里动手！
Not in my hall!
这孩子是作为使节来的
The boy came as an envoy.
我不允许在我的屋檐下流血
I'll not have bloodshed beneath my roof.
带路斯里斯王子去找他的龙
Take Prince Lucerys back to his dragon.
马上
Now.
注意！
Dokimarvose!
听我说 阿拉克斯！
Laehossa ynot, Arrax!
冷静！
Lykirī!
听着！
Ryptēs!
听话！
Rȳbās!
飞 阿拉克斯！
Sōvēs, Arrax!
傻瓜！瓦格哈尔！
Mittys! Vagus!
瓦格哈尔
伊蒙德的龙
快！转弯！
Aderī! Pālēs!
你欠了债
Jemēla gēlȳni enkā!
小子！
Taobus!
不 阿拉克斯
Daor, Arrax!
听话 阿拉克斯！往上飞！
Dohaerās, Arrax! Hepās, vēzot!
不 不 不 不 不！不 瓦格哈尔！不！
No, no, no, no, no! No, Vhagar! No!
不!
Daor!
听话 瓦格哈尔 不！
Serve me, Vhagar! No!
听话 瓦格哈尔！
Dohaerās, Vhagar!
瓦格哈尔！不！不！
Vhagar! No! No.